PETER NAUDUS

20653 CLOVER HILL RD, REMINGTON, VA 22734 | 917-689-8451 | USELINUX@GMAIL.COM

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I have almost two decades of professional experience as an enthusiastic, creative, and tenacious programmer. I have both the technical skills coupled with the passion to solve problems and implement robust, performant software. I am constantly striving, not only to improve myself, but to help those around me to do the same. I am currently a technical lead specializing in "big data" at Oracle.

SUMMARY OF SKILLS

- Programming Languages: Bash, C/C++, CSS, Go, Java, Javascript, HTML, PHP, Python
- Technologies: Docker, Git, Microservices
- Databases: Hadoop, HBase, LevelDB, MySQL, Oracle, PostgreSQL
- Interpersonal Skills: Agile development, Leadership, Technical writing
- Operating Systems: Windows, Linux

WORK HISTORY

Technical Lead at Oracle | February 2013 – Present

In addition to maintaining all responsibilities prior to the acquisition,

- Created technical designs and assisted in the porting of the python-based system to Java
- Eventually became the technical lead, where I implemented agile methodologies, coordinated tasks between multiple groups, and acted as an architect of many of the core systems
- Maintained this leadership position as we rearchitected the system as a fleet of microservices running on top of Kubernetes and Docker
- Also created and maintained the scripts which compiled, packaged, and versioned our releases

Software Engineer at DataRaker | May 2011 – February 2013

- Became the lead developer principally responsible for all code that comprised the back-end systems
- A key contributor to every portion of the development stack including: encoding/decoding
 of the HTable rows/keys, data loading API, the distributed map/reduce framework,
 aggregation engines, DAL (data access layer), multiple in-memory and disk-based caching
 schemes, data filtering, metric computation, a graph-based calculation engine, javascriptbased data visualizations, designed the HTML/CSS UI template
- Acted as a DevOps engineer, developing an automated system to provision, install, and configure our Hadoop/HBase clusters

Software Developer at ProQual-I.T. | March 2010 – May 2011

- Worked on a fingerprinting system for the DOD (Department of Defense), primarily working on a graph-based state machine that created, monitored and managed distributed tasks
- Contributed to other consulting projects, including a healthcare patient management system
- Also redesigned the company website from scratch

Proprietor at LinuxLefty Solutions | January 2008 – March 2010

- Founded LinuxLefty solutions which provided clients all around the world with a wide range of creative and affordable solutions
- Projects included: webmaster, web designer, SEO engineer, and architectural visualization

Intern at Defense Information Systems Agency | March 2005 – December 2007

• I wrote software to collect data statistics and generate utilization and performance statistics. I received training on OPNET network simulation and diagnostic tools, and installed, configured, and verified security on development servers.

Software Engineer at Vinci Systems | January 2003 – November 2004

- Was given sole responsibility to automate the manufacturing, functional, and stress testing of a PON (Passive Optical Network) and ONT (Optical Network Terminator) product line
- Achieved automation using TCL, TK, Expect, and PHP resulting in over 15,000 lines of combined code

Junior Tester at Advanced Switching Communications | April 2000 – December 2001

• Created automation scripts that helped reduce the total testing time by 10%, while bolstering the number and thoroughness of tests

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Science (BS) | Computer Science | George Mason University

· Minor in Math

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Troubled Youth Counselor at IBLP | February 2002 – December 2002

- Worked with juvenile delinquents, guiding them towards a lasting change of behavior and attitude
- Also taught TCL programming classes to students ages 11 to Adult

English Teacher at Peking University | Bejing, China | February 2008 – January 2010

• Training underprivileged Chinese English teachers on effective teaching methods. My class sizes varied widely from 20 to over sometimes over 200 students.